Osama Soliman

Software Developer

CONTACT

- +201063116380
- prof.o.soliman@gmail.com
- Shiben Al Kom, Egypt
- https://microsmsm.com

EDUCATION

V. Good

Faculty of Science (CS dep.) Shiben Al Kom, 2019

Good

Faculty of Pharmacy Tanta University, 2013 | 2015

SKILLS

- Frontend Web Development
- Cross-platform Mobile
 Development
- Backend Development
 Fundamentals
- Algorithms and DS Fundamentals
- OOP Fundamentals
- SEO
- UI/UX Design
- Social Media Marketing

Tools

Angular, JavaScript, TypeScipt, NodeJS, MongoDB, Express, NPM, Github, HTML5, CSS4. Windows, MacOS, Android, iOS, Ionic, Flutter, RN, NativeScript, Cordova

PROFILE

Over 6 years' experience in Software Development, I am a hard worker, fast learner, and self-motivated developer. I work well with teammates and enjoy getting the work completed in time and love handling new challenges.

I have over 3 years' experience working Remotely through platforms like Upwork/Hub staff, I am used to having a daily team meeting, discussing daily progress, also I am available for Travels when Needed.

EXPERIENCE

Founder & Cross-platform Mobile Developer

Dawaey | Shiben Al Kom | 2016-2020

Serving ~100,000 Healthcare providers in two countries using bleeding edge technologies, Offering high quality medical reference, Open source, and available for every platform saved ~500,000 hours to serve 5,000,000 patients till now. I worked with:

- UI Design and Development.
- Software Development for (Web, PWA, Android, iOS, WP, Windows and MacOS)
- Technical Leading for small team of (designer, backend and full stack developers)
- Digital Marketing, Firebase and Google Analytics

Open Source Contributor

Github | Global | 2017- Present

With tenth of open source projects and the need to Enhance the developer experience I have contributed to (IONIC, Webpack, Node.js, MDN).

I worked with:

- Enhancing the documentation consumed by millions of developers on MDN.
- Fixing some bugs in the most famous bundling tool Webpack
- Implementing new ES features inside the Node.js environment.
- Contributing to IONIC forums and trying to improve the docs.

Web and Mobile Development Freelancer

Upwork | Global | 2017- Present

I have over 3 years' experience working Remotely through platforms like Upwork/Hub staff, I am used to having a daily team meeting, discussing daily progress, also I am available for Travels when Needed.

- Produce fully functional mobile and web applications writing clean code.
- Design interfaces to improve user experience.
- Stay up-to-date with new technology trends.

Osama Soliman

Software Developer

AWARDS

Impacting ~200,000 developers on (StackOverflow)

Answering questions and impacting ~200,000 developers on StackOverflow during the past 957 days.

Impacting ~100,000 healthcare providers through (Dawaey)

Helping ~100,000 healthcare providers with newer and smart technologies.

Top 10% Overall developers on (Stackoverflow) for years 2016,2017 and 2018

Part of the top Stackoverflow answerers.

CERTIFICATIONS

JavaScript for Experienced Developers

Microsoft | 2016

Google Developer Challenge Scholarship

Udacity | 2017

LANGUAGES

English | Fluent Arabic | Native

FAVORITE BOOKS

- You Don't Know JavaScript
- Clean Code
- Eloquent JavaScript

EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)

Crypto Frontend Developer

ExKnox | Tennessee | 2017

Remote Lead developing UI/UX for Blockchain, Crypto Currency and Decentralized Apps.

At Exknox. It was a fun experience to help a little Startup in the USA in crypto-exchange and cryptocurrencies to evolve.

I was responsible for:

- Angular and little API development.
- The clientside works, from HTML to CSS to JavaScript.

Cross-platform Mobile Developer

Parent.eu | Denmark | 2017

Remote cross-platform mobile application developer, I was responsible for developing the application that takes care of children in pre-school and nurseries. Developing high quality cross platform apps. Optimizing performance, fixing bugs and implementing cool features. I used JavaScript, TypeScript, Ionic, Angular and some other cool bleeding-edge technologies to build the app. It was huge with over 50 screens to manage the whole system with a multi-user dashboard, check-in system, paper-less routines, child friends, social newsfeed, child progress, and graphs and other advanced programming stuff was there.

REFERENCES

Karim Mesallam

Technical Consultant
Paren.eu
karim.mesallam@gmail.com
+201022193223

Ehab Ahmed

Managing Director
Parent.eu
eng.ehabahmed@hotmail.com
+201002573257